A Guide to the Papers of the Kean Family
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Kean Family 1859-1951
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
1331-c
This collection consists of ca. 1745 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were originally loaned to the University of Virginia Library by Jefferson Randolph Kean, Clifton Forge, Virginia, on December 4, 1989, and renewed by his sister, Margaret Kean Rubel, on January 31, 1995.
Biographical/Historical Information
Robert Garlick Hill Kean (1828-1898) married 1) Jane Nicholas Randolph (1831-1868) on April 24, 1854
Their children: a) Lancelot Minor Kean (1856-1931) m. 1) Elizabeth Tucker Prescott 2) Martha Foster Murphy; b) Patsy Cary (Kean) Morris (1858-1939) m. John Speed Morris; c) Dr. Jefferson Randolph Kean (1860-1950); d) Robert Garlick Hill Kean, Jr. [1861-1883?];e) Lewis Randolph Kean (d. 1864); f) George Randolph Kean (1866-1869)
R.G.H. Kean married 2) Adelaide Navarro de Maret Prescott on January 14, 1874.
Dr. Jefferson Randolph Kean (1860-1950) married 1) Louise Hurlburt Young (1877-1915) on October 10, 1894. Their children: a) Martha Jefferson Kean (1895-?) m. William Chason; b) Robert Hill Kean (1900-?) m. Sarah Rice Elliott
Dr. J.R. Kean married 2) Cornelia Butler Knox on March 24, 1919.
For additional information see the two volumes of the Collected Papers of the Monticello Association of the Descendants of Thomas Jefferson especially the article Jane Nicholas Randolph and Robert Garlick Hill Kean by Robert Hill Kean and Jefferson Randolph Kean, in Volume II, Chapter XV, pages 92-102 (E332.76.S49).
Scope and Content
This collection consists of bound volumes and correspondence of the Kean family, ca. 1,745 items (13 Hollinger boxes, ca. 7 linear feet), [1859]-1951, chiefly the 39 diaries of Dr. Jefferson Randolph Kean(1860-1950) and other bound volumes, and the correspondence between Dr. Kean and other members of the Kean family. The largest group of correspondence consists of letters from his father, Robert Garlick Hill Kean, a lawyer in Lynchburg, Virginia, and a member of the University of Virginia Board of Visitors (appointed in 1872 and in 1890), to Dr. Jefferson Randolph Kean, 1879-1898, full of family news, Lynchburgevents, the University of Virginiaand commentary on Virginia and local politics.
This collection consists of two series: Series I: Bound Volumes (Boxes 1-4) and Series II: Correspondence (Boxes 5-13).
Dr. Jefferson Randolph Keankept the diaries from 1891 until his death in 1950. In the first volume, he states his purpose in keeping the diaries as to jot down daily occurrences, especially those of a social nature, including new acquaintances, marriages, births, and deaths. At the back of each volume, Dr. Kean usually kept lists of all these plus a list of all letters sent and received by month. He also attempted to index the more notable pages of his diaries and some of these indexed items will be mentioned in the following diary summaries. Most diaries have numerous references to family news and events and medical colleagues.
Diary Summaries (see Boxes 1-3)
Vol. 1 - Lynchburg(1891 Dec) - St. Augustine(1893 May), mentions Levy & Monticello, and Edgehill
Vol. 2 - St. Augustine(1893 May 9 -1894 Nov 19) - Key West Barracks(1894 Nov 20-1895 Apr 19)
Vol. 3 - Key West Barracks(1895 Apr 21-1897 Apr 5) -On Leave to St. Augustine, Lynchburg, Washington, New York, and Boston(1897 Apr 5-May 3) - Fort Warren, in Boston Harbor(1897 May 3-Sep 10)
Vol. 4 - Fort Warren(1897 Sep 11-1900 Nov 1) -Left for Quemados, Headquarters Department of Western Cuba(1900 Nov 1), mentions Walter Reed, W. C. Gorgas, the sinking of The Maine, the Spanish-American War, the Armistice
Vol. 5 - Cuba(1900 Nov 13-1902 May 20) -Left for Newport Newson 1902 May 20 -chiefly in Washington(1902 May 31-1904 Jun 2), mentions Walter Reed's Yellow Fever Experiments, the assassination of President William McKinley, and the Medical Reorganization Bill; Pages 6-10 of the diary include the Pine Ridge Campaign, South Dakota(1890 Nov 19-1891 Mar 27) from an earlier time in his career
Vol. 6 - New York City(1904 Jun 5) - Cuba(1907 Jan 31), mentions winning the Seaman's Prize Essay Award, an auto trip through the Valley of Virginia, appointed by President Theodore Rooseveltto the Central Committee of the American Red Cross, the San Franciscoearthquake, intervention in Cuba, Kean takes charge as Health Officer of Cuba, and visit to Panama
Vol. 7 - Cuba(1907 Feb 1) - Washington, D.C.(1909 Nov 24), mentions his health work in Cuba
Vol. 8 - Washington, D.C.(1909 Nov 25) - Los Angeles, California(1911 Jul 1), mentions Painted Deserttrip, his presence at the Maneuver Camp, San Antonio, due to the unrest in Mexico, and the Nicholas lands
Vol. 9 - Los Angeles, California(1911 Jul 1) - Lexington, Virginia(1912 Sep 15) mentions examination of rats for plague at San Juanand elsewhere, trip to Paris, sanitary survey conducted by Kean, Amundsen reaching the South Pole, Monticello Graveyard, and typhoid prevention
Vol. 10 - Washington(1912 Sep 28) - Ft. Leavenworth, Kansas(1914 Jul 14) includes family dates and genealogy, record of his foreign service with dates, list of correspondence with the Surgeon General's Office, and record of the first meeting of the Monticello Association
Vol. 11 - Ft. Leavenworth, Kansas(1914 Jul 18) - Washington, D.C.(1916 Mar 9), mentions outbreak of World War I, trip to Yellowstone Park
Vol. 12 - Washington, D.C.(1916 Mar 10) - Paris, France(1918 Feb 10), mentions preparations of the medical service for war, Monticello Association, mobilization of Base Hospitals, and Red Crosswork
Vol. 13 - Paris, France(1918 Feb 11) - Boston, Massachusetts(1919 Sep 7), describes his war work in Europe
Vol. 14 - Boston, Massachusetts(1919 Sep 9) - Boston, Massachusetts(1920 Oct 30)
Vol. 15 - Boston, Massachusetts(1920 Nov 1) - Boston, Massachusetts(1921 Nov 9), lists dates and places of his foreign service, homeopathic Base Hospitals, and trip to Europe
Vol. 16 - Boston, Massachusetts(1921 Nov 17 -1922 Nov 19)
Vol. 17 - Boston, Massachusetts(1922 Nov 24 -1923 Dec 8), mentions the death of President Wlliam J. Harding, accepts the position of editor of The Military Surgeon and secretaryship of the Association of Military Surgeons, sighting of the naval airship Shenandoah over Boston, and examination of some papers of his father's
Vol. 18 - Boston, Massachusetts(1923 Dec 13) - Ft. McIntosh, Texas(1924 Nov 16)
Vol. 19 - Washington, D.C.(1924 Nov 26 -1925 Oct 14)
Vol. 20 - Washington, D.C.(1925 Oct 15) - Walter Reed Hospital(1927 Apr 10), mentions the Walter Reed MemorialAssociation and Prohibition
Vol. 21 - Washington, D.C.(1927 Apr 10 -1928 Aug 31), mentions the Charles Lindberghflight, the Monticello Association, " Edgehill" and " Tuckahoe"
Vol. 22 - Washington, D.C.(1928 Sep 1 -1930 Mar 4), mentions Poplar Forestvisit (p. 102), and the Wall Street Stock Market Crash
Vol. 23 - Washington, D.C.(1930 Mar 8 -1931 Aug 20), mentions India& Gandhi(p. 179), and the Stuart portrait of Thomas Jefferson(p. 180)
Vol. 24 - Washington, D.C.(1931 Aug 21 -1932 Dec 24), contains genealogical notes, and mentions plans for the Thomas Jefferson Memorial, the Monticello Association, Prohibition, the Japanese seizure of Shanghai, the Lindbergh baby kidnapping, the flight of Amelia Earhart, the Bonus Army, and the Presidential election
Vol. 25 - Washington, D.C.(1932 Dec 25 -1934 Jul 15), mentions Franklin Rooseveltand the "New Deal" (pages 110-111), John L. Newcomb's election as President of the University of Virginia(p. 86)
Vol. 26 - Washington, D.C.(1934 Jul 21 -1935 Aug 31), mentions the Thomas Jefferson Memorials, the Walter Reed Memorial Association, and his resignation as secretary of the Association of Military Surgeons
Vol. 27 - Washington, D.C.(1935 Sep 1 -1936 Nov 12), includes his personal health record, mentions the award of the Grand Cross Order of Merit of Carlos Finlay by the President of Cuba, and the conquest of Ethiopiaby Mussolini
Vol. 28 - Washington, D.C.(1936 Nov 15 -1938 Mar 31), mentions the Jefferson cups, King Edward's VIII love affair, the annexation of Austriaby Hitler, Democratic conference, Hitler, the Jews of Europe, the Sully portrait of Martha Jefferson Randolph, Monticello Association, the North Pole, the sinking of the U.S. gunboat The Panay in Nankingby the Japanese, Romania, the inauguration of President Franklin D. Roosevelt, the Supreme Court
Vol. 29 - Washinton, D.C.(1938 Apr 1 -1939 May 4), mentions aviation, especially Howard Hughes, and the Thomas Jefferson Memorial Commission
Vol. 30 - Washington, D.C.(1939 May 7 -1940 Jun 9), mentions Association of Military Surgeons International Congress, American Military History Institute, blitzkriegs, China, Battle of Flanders, Winston Churchill, Dunkirk, Finland, France, Hitler, Stalin, Income Tax, Jefferson Memorial, Japan& China, the Jefferson cups, the Netherlands, Norway, the capture of Parisby the Nazis, Russian attack on Finland, strike of W.P.A. workers, Wounded Knee, the invasion of Polandand other war events
Vol. 31 - Washington, D.C.(1940 Jun 10 -1941 May 13), mentions the Democratic convention, the Lend-Lease Bill, the U.S. take-over of Greenlandto establish an air base, Income Tax, the Thomas Jefferson Memorial Commission, Dr. Fiske Kimball, labor strikes, Defense Production, the Oaksin Washington, D.C., numerous references to the war, the Republican National Convention, air raids over England, the Walter Reed Memorial Association, and the destruction of Westminster Abbeyand Plymouth
Vol. 32 - Washington, D.C.(1941 May 14 -1942 Apr 2), mentions the British Navy, Winston Churchill, President Franklin D. Roosevelt, Rudolf Hess' flight, retirement of Chief Justice Hughes, the League of Nations, labor, death of Kaiser Wilhelm, Fiske Kimball, "Right-to-Work," Monticello Association, Thomas Jefferson Memorialand the inscriptions, Stalin-Hitler pact, General Douglas MacArthur, Congress and lobbies, Pearl Harbor, the progress of the war, and submarines
Vol. 33 - Washington, D.C.(1942 Apr 3 -1943 Feb 7), mentions Dr. Harry Clemons, Thomas Jefferson Memorial Commission, the Presidential election, rationing, the Gorgas medal, violin belonging to Thomas Jefferson, Dr. Fiske Kimball, Eddie Rickenbacker, saboteurs, suppression of bad news, Supreme Court, U-Boats, and much war news
Vol. 34 - Washington, D.C.(1943 Feb 8 -Dec 31), mentions the Thomas Jefferson Bicentennial, Winston Churchill, rationing, Mississippi Valleyfloods, Keangenealogy, Thomas Jefferson Memorial, Thomas Jeffersonportraits on exhibit in the National Gallery of Art, penicillin, Montgomery and the Eighth Army, the Moscow Convention, coal strike, war news, Thomas Jeffersondescendants, and the U-Boat menace
Vol. 35 - Washington, D.C.(1944 Jan 1 -Nov 10), mentions bureaucratic government, Thomas Jefferson Memorial Commission, Cuban election, nomination of Governor Dewey of New York, D-Day, Fiske Kimball, Italian King Umbertoretirement, invasion of Germanyand other war news, robot planes, sketch of Marshall Petain, Monticello Association, capture of Rome, Jefferson and Abraham Lincoln, assassination attempt on Hitler, and the presidential election
Vol. 36 - Washington, D.C.(1944 Nov 15 -1945 Aug 21), mentions the Atomic Bomb, Atlantic Charter, Communism, concentration camps, United Nations, General Dwight Eisenhower, Hitler, Mussolini, war news, Okinawa, Poland, capture of Berlin, war criminals, Yalta Conference, Potsdam Conference, death of President Franklin D. Roosevelt, President Harry S. Truman, San Francisco Conference, and British elections
Vol. 37 - Washington, D.C.(1945 Aug 21 -1946 Jun 26), mentions Atomic Bomb, Senator Byrd, Bernard Baruch, United Nations, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Fiske Kimball, labor, Nurembergtrials, the Red Cross, V-J Day, Secretary Stimson, politics, E.R. Stettinius, Japan, and end of war
Vol. 38 - Washington, D.C.(1946 Jul 1 -1948 Mar 11), mentions air crashes, Bikiniand the Atomic Bomb, Princess Elizabethof Great Britain, murder of Gandhi, personal health notes, Thomas Jefferson, Nazi criminals, labor, politics, Russia, Monticello Association, Henry Wallace, and President Harry S. Truman
Vol. 39 - Washington, D.C.(1947 Jan 15 -1950 Jul) "And So to Bed A Diary," mentions Secretary of State George Marshall, Monticello Association, John L. Lewis, Secretary of War Henry L. Stimson, Great Britain's loss of power, Thomas Jefferson, Taft-Hartley Labor Bill, India, Atomic control, General George Marshall, General Dwight D. Eisenhower, Abraham Lincoln, Thomas Jeffersonand the Unitarian Church, Soviet movement into Czechoslovakia, the Berlinblockade, disposal of his books and papers, Korea, publication of Dumas Malone's book about Thomas Jefferson, and publication of Volume one of The Papers of Thomas Jefferson.
A list of the other bound volumes can be found in the box listing for boxes three and four at the end of the guide.
Letters from R. G. H. Keanto Dr. Jefferson Randolph Kean
These letters begin with J. Randolph Keanat the University of Virginiain 1879 where he attended the Medical School until 1883 June 25. His other locations during his correspondence with his father include:
at home in Lynchburg(1883 Jun 27-Aug)
New York City(1883 Sep 26-1884 Feb 14)
Ft. Sill, Indian Territory, Oklahoma(present day Comanche County), as assistant and post surgeon (1884 Jun 16-1887 Nov 30)
on leave from Ft. Sill(1887 Nov 30-1888 Jan 28)
return to Ft. Sill(1888 Feb -1891 Dec)
at Pine Ridge Agency, South Dakota(1890-1891 Winter)
on leave in Lynchburg(1891 Jun)
on leave in Lynchburgdue to bullet wound (1891 Dec)
Captain & Post Surgeon, St. Francis Barracks, St. Augustine(1892 Mar 23)
marriage of J. Randolph Keanto Louise H. Young(1894 Oct 11)
orders to go to Key West Barracks(1894 Oct 31)
orders to go to Ft. Warren, Boston Harbor(1897 Mar 16)
arrival at Ft. Warren(1897 May 3)
war declared on Spain(1898 Apr 25)
R.G.H. Keanvery ill, J.Randolph Keanat Lynchburg(1898 May 16-24; Jun 2-15)
R.G.H. Keandies (1898 Jun 13)
J. Randolph Keanleaves Ft. Warrento report to Jacksonville, Florida(1898 Jun 24)
Subjects mentioned in letters of R.G.H. Keaninclude:
1883
controversy over boarding houses at the University of Virginia(Apr 6)
Lynchburgelections and a legal case involving a railroad (May 18)
a big fire at Lynchburgon May 29th (Jun 1)
advice that medical service in the Army preferable to private practice (Jun 14)
discussion about John Warwick Daniel's speech at the unveiling of Lee's statue at Lexington(Jun 30)
Kean's dislike of William Mahoneand discussion about the elections (Nov 5 & 18; Dec 11)
Anthony Trollope's autobiography (Dec 3)
the growth of industry in the South and the importance of her ports (Dec 11)
sightings of Robert G.H. Kean, Jr.(Sep 26, Oct 24; 1884 Jan 9, Feb 3; 1886 Apr 15)
1884
death of Aunt Mary Randolph(Jun 26)
train wreck near [Lovetown?] (Jun 30)
discussion of early Civil War Service of R.G.H. Kean& the army commission of J. Randolph Kean(Aug 3)
preparation for the case of Noble vs Davis (Aug 11)
Mahoneism & local elections (Sep 3)
local adultery scandal involving Dr. E.H. Murrellat the Springs (Sep 8)
comments about upcoming elections (Nov 1, 15)
Kean's speech at Washington & Lee(Nov 28)
1885
use of morphine in pregnancy (Jan 7, 28)
vacant professorship in Law and Chemistry at the University of Virginia(Jan 7)
controversy over Indian lands (Jan 28)
strike of South Pacific Railroadworkers, "silver politics" and economics (Mar 10)
the President's proclamation re the settlers in the Oklahoma Indian Territory(Mar 19)
mention of proposal to use "colored troops" in Central America(Mar 30)
dedication of the Observatory at the University of Virginia(Apr 9 & 19)
worries over the changes in faculty at the University of Virginia(May 16)
Jefferson Harrisonat Edgehillapparently insane (Jun 10, 15)
death of little Addie (Jun 20)
death of little Lancelot and R.G.H. Kean's sister, Nannie (Jul 17)
burial of Dr. John Staige Davis at the UVA cemetery; death of General Grant (Jul 27)
T. J. Levy barring access to the Monticello burying ground (Aug 19)
description of the [Denmark ?] circulating library out of Raleigh, N.C.(Sep 25)
local politics, including Fitzhugh Lee's success in his Democratic canvass for the Governor's race (Sep 25)
controversy in their synod over the teaching of evolution (Oct 24)
his support for Civil Service Reform (Mar 30; Nov 23; Dec 12)
the solution for the "Indian Problem" (Nov 17)
1886
essay by R.G.H. Kean re "Jefferson as Legislator" (Jan 4; 1887 Jan 8)
bankruptcy of John Morris causes bankruptcy of R.G.H. Kean& Lancelot Kean; Kean wants to give Universal History formerly belonging to Thomas Jefferson to his son, Dr. Kean (Jan 23) the possibility of working on a Jefferson concordance; his wonder at Jefferson's versatility (Mar 7, 27)
the death of Lanty's boy (Mar 13)
reference to a strike in New York by the Knights of Labor(Mar 27)
mention of the Andersonville Prison, federal prisoners, and General Grant's policy of attrition (Mar 27)
reference to railroad riots and bloodshed which he sees as a war between classes, Capital & Trade vs Labor, and other social changes (Apr 11)
financial details; his concern over the loss of his law library due to bankruptcy (Apr 15 & 25, May 2)
sale of Kean's house and property; views on local option; his speech against Prohibition pushed by the Methodists and Baptists; and his views on religious intolerance which is hindered by the wide diversity of sects present in the United States (Apr 25)
the "prohibition election" in Lynchburg; his low opinion of John Morris; daughter Patty is working while pregnant but will probably go to Edgehillfor her confinement; and General Early's desire for him to run for Commonwealth's Attorney (May 2 & 4)
Kean's bankruptcy and bad behavior of John Morris: and the rejection of Mr. Button by the Senate and Button's quarrel with J.R. [Mabee?](May 15)
discussion of alcohol; belief that John Morrisdepends on his wife or friends for support (May 23 & 31)
attempted suicide of Mrs. Nowlin (Jun 14)
arrest of George A. Kinnearfor the theft of registered letters at the post office (Jun 29)
UVA gossip about Dr. James F. Harrisonwho was caught engaging in "criminal amour" with George F. Holmes' "cracked or eccentric daughter" and was urged by the Board of Visitors to leave his position in the School of Medicineand take up farming in Prince William County(Jul 17)
the difficult delivery and death of a neighbor, Mary (Mrs. Clayton Manson) (Jul 17, 26 & 29)
changes at the University of Virginia Medical Schooland faculty (Aug 9)
concerns over the agriculture and economy of Virginia -many young men going out West (Aug 16)
discussion of Civil Service Reform, the Democratic Nominating Convention at Lynchburgto replace Daniel and the debt question (Aug 22; Sep 1)
description of local earthquake (Sep 1)
Patsy's milk business begun (Sep-Oct)
a legal case involving a company who manufactures cigarette making machines and the inventor of its most successful model (Oct)
the burning of the Medical Hall at the University of Virginia(Nov 26)
wants J. Randolph Keanto send his fossil discovery to University of Virginia; discussion of the possible ramifications of a Comanche word which might mean "elephant" (Dec 21)
1887
[John W.] "Daniel's morbid greed for patronage" and public drunkenness in Washington(Jan 8; Mar 1)
comments re Uncle Tom's Cabin (Mar 1)
the effect of railroads on agricultural land (Mar 13)
Prescott Keanreceives two young alligators from Louisiana(Apr 11)
St. Paul'sneed for a new church building (Apr 17)
young boys addicted to cigarettes; the closing of the school at Edgehill(Apr 24)
reference to Louis Pasteur's germ theory (Apr 29)
long discussion on the participation of the Knights of Laborin the municipal elections with the political canvassing of "all the Negroes, most of the more ignorant mechanics and pretty much all the white riffraff"; belief that William Mahoneis manipulating the Knights of Labor in order to succeed H.H. Riddlebergerin the Senate; and Wilson Randolphhas returned to the nail factory (May 7 & 29; Jun 12)
many young Virginians heading West to make a living (Jun 4)
the return of old Confederate battle flags protested by the G.A.R. Union veterans; his opinion of General Thomas Rosser(Jun 19)
visit to Wythevilleand the U.S. Fish Hatchery(Jun 27)
election of city officers by the new City Council of Lynchburg; Kean re-elected City Attorney; his "fishing excursion" (Jul 3)
plans to visit J. Randolph Keanat Ft. Sillfor a month in August ([Jul 29])
Lanty's preparations to leave for Sioux City, Iowato make a living (Oct 2)
1888
frequent use of morphine in treatments by doctors (Feb 13)
J. Randolph Kean's transfer to Ft. Robinson (Dawes County) Nebraska(Mar 13)
the double sin of C.W. [Price ?]who not only decided to run as an independent after his loss in the primary but also kept a mistress and bought her a house (Apr 22)
the shortage of nurses who are engaged for four weeks service in advance to care for new babies (Apr 22)
daughter Pat delivers a boy almost without help (May 6)
Addie goes to Philadelphiafor treatment at a private hospital (May 3-Oct 1)
trip of J. Randolph Keanto Rawlinsand Green River City, Wyoming Territory(Jun-Jul)
U.S./Canada disagreement under Grover Clevelandand Kean's good opinion of Philip Sheridan(Aug 25)
Pat and R.G.H. Keanattend the Exposition at Richmond(Oct 22)
discussion of the "dirty turmoil of politics," approval of President Grover Cleveland(Nov 4, 11)
"the race question," sexual relations between the races, criticism of Darwin & Huxley (Dec 8)
1889
working on a paper for the annual State Bar Association meeting called "Judiciary of Virginia" (Jan 20)
decision of vestry of St. Paul's Churchto build a new church on the Slaughter lot (Jan 20)
description of the appearance of Crown Prince Rudolph of Austria-Hungary(Feb 3)
overdoses of quinine, opium, and other drugs in the neighborhood (Feb 3)
his mistake in not networking during his legal career (Feb 11)
belief that Indians in the future will virtually disappear or mix with white or Negro races (Feb 17)
the altercation between Senators [William Eaton?] Chandlerand [ Joseph Clay Stiles Blackburn?] in Committee (Feb 24)
the problem of lobbyists and their influence in Congress (Mar 3)
discussion of "the Negro question," women in French society and the drawbacks in the liberty of American women in choosing husbands (Mar 10)
death of General Hatch (Apr 16)
discussion about the admission of African Americans to church administration and voting, especially the Episcopal Church and his belief that they would vote as a block (May 29)
Kean is Chairman of the Lynchburgdelegation to the State Democratic Convention at Richmond(Aug 10)
Hattie Drakehas gone into professional nursing and is prepared to serve in Europewith the Red Crossin military hospitals if war should break out (Aug 18 & 28)
stamp collecting (Aug 28)
John Morrishas left to work in the Indian Territory in Caney, Kansas(Nov 1 & 22)
trouble with [Jefferson ?] Levyover the legal rights of the heirs of Jefferson Randolphto access the Monticello burying ground; fox hunting in Albemarle; lack of confidence in juries (Nov 8)
J. Randolph Keanwill be promoted to Captain in February of 1890 (Dec 4, 15)
description of Pat's new home in Caney, Kansas(Dec 22)
1890
Lynchburgin the throes of prohibition fever; Kean's disapproval that both sexes and races are allowed to speak out against alcohol on the same platform in the spirit of social equality; Prescott Keanhas lost almost all of his belongings in a fire in one of Abbott's school buildings (Jan 12)